Matthew B. Bowler www.matthewbbowler.com

1210 North 16th Street Jacksonville Beach, Florida 32250 Phone: 904-351-8487

Portfolio Site: matthewbbowler.com
Email: mbowler03@gmail.com
Github: github.com/mbowler03

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/matthewbowler03</u>

SUMMARY

I am an organized and dedicated finance and sales professional with a successful track record of implementing and completing projects. Currently, I am in the process of becoming a "full stack developer" in order to merge my current finance skills and experience with new and emerging technologies.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Owner, North Florida Healthy Vending

2018 to Present

• Owner of several healthy vending machines located in various private and charter schools in Jacksonville, Florida...

Loan Officer, BBVA Compass Bank

2018 to 2019

• Loan Officer to four BBVA locations in Jacksonville, Florida

Senior Loan Officer, Carrington Mortgage Jacksonville, Florida

2015 to 2018

- Closed over 23 million in FHA and VA mortgages in 2016 becoming one of the companies leading producers
- Obtained the promotion of "Senior Loan Officer" during the first month of eligibility by closing an average of over 14 loans per month since date of hire
- Obtained and currently hold thirty-two originators licenses

Account Manager, XPO Logistics Jacksonville, Florida

2013 to 2015

- Specialized in the management of the transportation needs of large retail clients
- Solicited new business obtained from paid sales leads, research, social media, and referrals

Loan Originator, PHH Mortgage Jacksonville, FL

2011 to 2013

- Originated Mortgage Loans under Private Label Solutions for a variety of companies including: Charles Schwab, Merrill Lynch, E*Trade, TIAA-Cref, Ameriprise, and Keybank
- Participated in federal refinance program called HARP which includes but is not limited to effectively matching a

variety of clients needs to the most beneficial product while adhering to continually changing regulations

• Obtained and held twenty-two originators licenses

Executive Director, Riverside Avondale Development Organization 2006 to 2011 Jacksonville, FL

- Supervised all business activities, including staff, finances, production, marketing and sales
- Provided oversight of internal and external audits and applicable governmental filings
- Secured a minimum of \$125,000 per year in grants and donations annually
- Increased housing production by 300%, expanded service boundaries, and conducted all predevelopment activities for two future signature projects
- Served as a leader in the implementation of processes under the federal Neighborhood Stabilization Program
- Initiated a new internal marketing strategy to include a comprehensive website, annual fundraiser, electronic
- and direct mail newsletter, an annual report, and an upgrade of all existing marketing materials
- Implemented a green initiative for all new projects in order to adhere to Florida Green Building Standards
- Strengthened a volunteer board of directors by recruiting and training new leaders from the local community

Vice President, Operation New Hope Jacksonville, FL

2000-2006

- Conducted research and repair of property titles including removal and payment of liens and assessed taxes
- Purchased more than sixty properties in the downtown Jacksonville area through grants and lines of credit
- Determined project feasibility by input and analysis of budgets, subcontractor bids, and subsidy availability
- Analyzed budgets to determine accurate revenue and expenditures and projected cash flow
- Assisted in raising funds for the organization through grant writing and tax credit submissions
- Sold and marketed all existing housing inventory
- Collaborated with a board of directors on a continual basis

EDUCATION

University of Central Florida

 Certificate of Completion from 24 Week Coding BootCamp with a concentration on Javascript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, React.js, MySQL, Node.js, Express.js, and PHP- Currently enrolled (June 2020 Completion date)

University of North Florida Jacksonville, FL

• Bachelor's Degree of Business Administration- Business Management